Guide to the Constance Curry Papers, 1958-2010s RL.11530
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Constance Curry papers
1958-2010s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Curry, Constance, 1933-
RL.11530
0.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains subject files, clippings, and reunion materials collected by Constance Curry, a civil rights activist and member of SNCC's executive board. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Constance Curry Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of Curry's early SNCC documents, including records of outsider support, as well as clippings and ephemera from the Mississippi Freedom Project and other SNCC initiatives. Also contains Curry's subject files on figures like Ella Baker and Stokely Carmichael (Kwame Ture), and clippings from various SNCC reunions and anniversaries in the 1990s and 2000s. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African American History and Culture.
Civil rights movements -- Mississippi; Mississippi Freedom Project; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Carmichael, Stokely; Baker, Ella; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
- SNCC Early Days Formation, 1958-1961, 1964 (Box 1)
  Scope and Content Note
  Documents related to the foundation and formation of the SNCC.
- Outside Support SNCC 1960 (Box 1)
  Documents that indicate who supported SNCC in its early days.
- The Student Voice SNCC, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  Photocopies of original SNCC newspaper (entitled The Student Voice) articles.
- Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Mississippi Freedom Summer, 1964 DNC, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
- Ella Baker-SNCC, 1982-2000 (Box 1)
  Scope and Content
  Clippings and ephemera about the life and participation of Ella Baker
- SNCC Trinity Conference (Casey's Paper), 1988 (Box 1)
- SNCC 40th Anniversary Conference, 1997, 2000 (Box 1)
- Mississippi Freedom Summer coverage, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
  Articles and documents related to the Mississippi Freedom Summer and its impact.
- SNCC 50th Anniversary Planning Committee, 2009 (Box 1)
- SNCC (2009) 50th- Beginning, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
- SNCC (2010) 50th Anniversary Conference, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
- Kwame Ture/Stokely Carmichael, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
  Documents (including an interview) about the life of Stokely Carmichael (who later changed his name to Kwame Ture).
- Greensboro Sit-ins Clippings, 1980s-2010s (Box 1)
  Newspaper clippings about the Greenboro sit-ins (written years after the sit-ins occurred).